crochetidea.com 2018-12-17

# Privacy Policy - Crochet Ideas

Crochet Idea (“ **Crochet Idea** “) operates http://crochetidea.com and may operate other websites. It is Crochet Idea’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites. We do comply with General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) (EU) 2016/679.

### Website Visitors

Like most website operators, Crochet Idea collects **non-personally-identifying** information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Crochet Idea’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Crochet Idea’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Crochet Idea may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

### Data Controller

Crochet Idea is the controller of any personally-identifiable-information gathered by Crochet Idea.

Contact us at any time to:

  * Request access to any information that Crochet Idea has about you
  * Correct any information that Crochet Idea has about you
  * Delete any information that Crochet Idea has about you

If you have any additional questions about Crochet Idea’s collection and storage of data, please contact us at: admin@crochetidea.com

## Information Collection And Use

We collect several different types of information for various purposes to provide and improve our Service to you.

### Types of Data Collected

#### Personal Identifiable Information

While using our Service, we may ask you to provide us with – or gather automatically – certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you (“Personal Data”). Personally identifiable information collected by Crochet Idea includes:

  * Cookies and Usage Data
  * Your computer’s IP address
  * Your email address (if you’ve left a comment on the site)

#### Usage Data

We collect information about how our Service is accessed and used (“Usage Data”). This Usage Data may include information such as your computer’s Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.

#### Tracking & Cookies Data

We use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track the activity on our Service and hold certain information.

Cookies are files with small amount of data which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. Tracking technologies also used are beacons, tags, and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyze our Service.

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service.

Examples of Cookies we use:

  * **Session Cookies.** We use Session Cookies to operate our Service.
  * **Preference Cookies.** We use Preference Cookies to remember your preferences and various settings.
  * **Security Cookies.** We use Security Cookies for security purposes.

#### IP Address

Any time you visit this website, a record of that visit is stored on this website’s servers. This data is used to identify any technical issues with the website and is stored by a 3rd party for 36 months.

#### Email Address

If you leave a comment on this website, you are required to include an email address. This email address is not displayed publicly but is available to the website administrator and stored on the website’s servers until such time as the comment is deleted. That information is used to determine whether future comments should be automatically approved or manually reviewed by the website administrator before the comment can be published in order to reduce spam.  
You may request that your comment and email address stored on the website’s servers be deleted at any time by contacting the administrator by sending an email address to admin@crochetidea.com.

## Use of Data

Crochet Idea uses the collected data for various purposes:

  * To provide and maintain the Service
  * To notify you about changes to our Service
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Service when you choose to do so
  * To provide customer care and support
  * To provide analysis or valuable information so that we can improve the Service
  * To monitor the usage of the Service
  * To detect, prevent and address technical issues

Crochet Idea only discloses visitor IP addresses, logged in user information and commenter IP addresses and emails under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that commenter IP addresses and email addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog/site where the comment was left.

Visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

## Transfer Of Data

Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.

If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data, including Personal Data, to the United States and process it there.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

Crochet Idea will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.

## Disclosure Of Data

### Legal Requirements

Crochet Idea may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:

  * To comply with a legal obligation
  * To protect and defend the rights or property of Crochet Idea
  * To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Service
  * To protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the public
  * To protect against legal liability

## Security Of Data

The security of your data is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

## Service Providers

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service (“Service Providers”), to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.

These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

### Analytics

We may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of our Service.

  * Google Analytics
  * Google Webmaster Tools/Google Search Console

### Aggregated Statistics

Crochet Idea may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. Crochet Idea may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Crochet Idea does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described above.

## Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Crochet Idea discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Crochet Idea’s behalf or to provide services available at Crochet Idea’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Crochet Idea’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Crochet Idea will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Crochet Idea discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Crochet Idea believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Crochet Idea, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an Crochet Idea website and have supplied your email address, Crochet Idea may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Crochet Idea and our products. If you send us a request (for example via email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Crochet Idea takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

## Business Transfers

If Crochet Idea, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Crochet Idea goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Crochet Idea may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

## Links To Other Sites

Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.

We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.

### Ads

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Crochet Idea and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Crochet Idea may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Crochet Idea’s sole discretion. Crochet Idea encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. If you have a http://crochetidea.com account, you might also receive an alert informing you of these changes. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

Back to top

## Contact Information

If you have any questions about our privacy policy or data collection and usage, please contact the website administrator at admin@crochetidea.com.
